I will show you some of the steps I took to speed up my video recording.
As you can see, you can search for physical properties on our Bilibili homepage when I did a live stream with Zach last year.
Okay, let's get started.
Let me introduce myself first.
Hello everyone, I am Sherry from Marvelous Designer.
I am responsible for teaching, making, training, and technical support for Marvelous Designer teams in China.
If you have any questions about Marvelous Designer, you can add our Q&A group and send me an email.
Okay.
Okay, let's get started.
Today, we are going to talk about making Marvelous Designer clothes.
Why did I choose this topic?
Because on Monday, there were some friends in the group who wanted to learn how to make Marvelous Designer clothes.
At that time, I said that Marvelous Designer had never been taught before.
Then I took a look and found out that it was related to Hanfu.
So I prepared a tutorial on how to make Marvelous Designer clothes.
In fact, Marvelous Designer clothes are all relatively simple and unified.
In the process of making Marvelous Designer clothes, you may need to constantly change the GPU and CPU simulation to make your simulation more stable and smooth.
Okay, let's get started.
First of all, let's learn how to make Marvelous Designer clothes.
How to complete the main body part, the collar, and the shape.
So the basic thing is to first reduce, for example, the surfaceight of the virtual model and the collar of the costume.
Well, how do we adjust the collar of the costume?
Let's take a look at the inside of this dress.
When you make a dress that looks a little bit like a Chinese dress,
because it is a collar, and it is close to the neck,
you need to position the collar first.
So when we are making it, we will push the collar in a little bit.
Then the front and back pieces need to match.
Put the collar in first.
Because you want it to be close enough to the neck,
when you make the collar, it will fit.
Of course, if you want to make a collar that doesn't fit,
then you can do it.
You don't need to make it so close.
Yes, the neck of this model is still very long.
Then we select these two threads,
check the length of its 2D line,
and make a long-shape version of the collar that matches it.
If you don't have the experience of playing the board,
then you don't need to worry.
You first create a long-shape version,
then we can fix it little by little.
Make a horizontal and vertical version first.
When we sew it, you have to pay attention.
I only sewed this board and collar here.
I didn't sew its front and back middle lines together.
It's more convenient for us to modify the board later.
Because if you sew the front and back together now,
this sewing line itself will also affect its structure.
It can't go down in a natural state,
and let you see where you need to adjust.
Okay, then let's take a look at this board.
First of all, the collar of a person is a three-dimensional structure.
Then your collar has a higher back middle,
and the front collar is relatively low.
When we create this board,
you can also raise the back middle a little bit.
Of course, I made this structure because of my own reasons.
It's because we need to turn this line into a curve later,
so I adjusted it like this.
Of course, in the process you usually do,
you can also adjust it according to my steps.
Okay, then after I moved the back middle line up,
it is now a diagonal line.
It also matches the collar of our model.
The front middle is low and the back middle is high.
But after I changed this to a diagonal line,
there will be a problem.
Now the upper corner is a sharp corner,
which is pointed out.
So now if you put the back middle together,
the part of the overlap in the middle
will become the excess amount.
It will squeeze your collar out.
Do you understand?
So we will push this point in a little bit.
Then after it is pushed in,
the excess amount of overlap will disappear.
We can wait a moment and then we are ready to sew it up.
Now this line,
you can see that we have a basic logic
when we are balancing the board.
That is, the position of the balance,
it has to be 180 degrees.
It will be a flat corner.
It won't have the corner protruding out.
The corner protruding out or the corner sticking in,
it will cause your board shape
to look like some strange places
or some sharp corners protruding out.
So when we are balancing,
you can see that our back middle
is more than 90 degrees.
We also try to keep this corner 90 degrees, right?
Then now the collar side,
is this corner a sharp corner?
It is protruding out.
Then during the sewing process,
it will definitely have some problems,
or it may affect your overall shape afterwards.
This point will stick together.
So now I just have to make sure
that its slope does not change.
I want to make this corner 90 degrees,
so I will change this straight line to a curve line.
This way,
it can make this corner and this corner
as close as possible to 90 degrees.
Do you understand?
Then we simulate it again.
So everyone usually thinks that
you don't have to remember
the logic of creating too many boards.
You can just say that
while adjusting,
while observing the state of the 3D window,
just say that
when you usually create boards,
you can remember
that I try to make the four corners of a board
are all 90 degrees.
Then no matter what,
when two boards are sewn together,
it is only 90 degrees plus 90 degrees,
which is 180 degrees.
It will stick together,
which is 180 degrees,
which is flat.
Then,
if you look at the top here,
if I just maintained that it is a straight line,
then here,
it will have a little bit of a protruding look,
right?
Because our board,
observe this board,
it is now at the bottom of a protruding curve line.
If there is still a straight line here,
there will be more in the middle,
there will be more material,
and there will be less on both sides.
When it looks in the 3D window,
it will look like there is a piece of fabric here.
So we use the curve line
to adjust it here first.
And this can also make it 90 degrees in all four corners.
Okay.
Then this is also a relatively fine adjustment.
In the usual process,
you don't need to be exactly the same as me,
just a little bit,
very fine adjustment.
You can roughly pull a curve,
and then take a look.
Okay.
Now we are going back to this model.
Let's see if there is still an extra part in the back of it.
Right?
Okay.
Here we see there is an extra part.
So we just push this point in.
We remove the extra part.
Okay.
After removing it,
is this corner sharp again?
This corner is crooked again.
So what are we going to do with this curve line?
Move this curve line up.
Because we want it to keep 90 degrees in both corners as much as possible.
Okay.
After moving it like this,
we will simulate it again.
You will find that it fits.
This is a little trick for us to adjust the collar.
You can also use this method
to adjust the collar in the future.
After that,
we will add a round-shape curve line to the front collar here
to make it round.
Okay.
After that,
I will continue to talk to you about some of our knowledge about the pattern.
Okay.
Then it is to make a big sound.
When making costume or fairy-tale style clothes,
we first change the posture of the virtual model to T-pose.
This is to make it easier for us to wear the sleeves in the back.
Because the back of the sleeve is a little bit too wide.
We can wear the sleeves in the back.
Because the sleeves of those costume designs are all horizontal and vertical.
And then the sleeves are very large.
If you keep wearing it with A-pose,
this version is not very easy to arrange.
We all use T-pose arrangement.
Of course, if you want to use A-pose,
you can do that.
Then we can look at the final version of this costume.
In fact,
the costume of the ancient style,
or our Hanfu,
its lines are basically straight.
Horizontal vertical lines.
It's just a little bit more or a little bit less fabric.
So in fact,
before you asked me to explain the ancient costume,
I said,
oh, in fact, this version is very simple.
You just have to make the line horizontal and vertical.
So what I'm using here is a T-pose version.
But,
except for the collar here,
because its collar still maintains some features of modern clothing.
It has a curve line.
There is a loop today.
Then the line on our side,
we also make it,
like the shoulder line here,
we make it flat.
Try to be flat.
You have a little bit of slanted to match this virtual model.
Naturally,
it's the state of hammering with both hands.
Your shoulder line is slanted.
It doesn't matter if you give it a little bit of slanted.
Then for our sleeves,
you can make it a straight line later.
What I'm doing here is still,
it's more basic.
I have two points on the same level line,
that is, on the vertical line.
Then delete all the curve points of this line.
Then for the costume sleeves,
it's usually the sleeves will be bigger.
The material under the leaf will flow more.
Then we move the bottom of the leaf down a little bit.
Okay,
because what we're doing now is a basic board.
This board is the inner layer of the clothes.
After that,
our board shape will be reattached.
This board comes out to be modified.
So let's match it with the virtual model first.
Then by the way,
some of my friends said that
this is me.
How come there is no cutout after the cutout is poured in?
This cutout is a virtual model.
It's the same as the X axis of our coordinate axis.
A cutout of the banana.
So if your 2D model,
that is, if you can't find a virtual model in the 2D window,
it's best to see if your model is not in the center of the coordinate,
not at the coordinate point.
Okay,
then let's push the two sides in a little bit.
It's because it's now the sleeve.
The shoulder line is a little too out of place.
If we look at it directly now,
this large version of it,
we will feel that it has a little more sleeves here.
But it doesn't matter.
Wait a minute,
the sleeves will look good when they are installed.
Okay,
there are a lot of hanfu panels.
In fact,
you usually search on Baidu or Pinterest,
there are a lot of hanfu panels that can be used.
Well,
I'm here because I think the hanfu panel is actually okay.
It's not a very difficult panel to draw.
I just drew it by hand.
Okay,
I made a sleeve here.
The sleeves here,
we also draw a rectangular panel first.
Then,
create a symmetrical panel.
Because the old-fashioned sleeves,
the front and back panels are actually not much different.
And then the sleeve panel,
especially the sleeve panel,
its front and back panels are basically symmetrical.
So we use the symmetry function first,
so that the front and back panels are symmetrical.
But here,
don't choose to match the panel and the sewing line.
Because we don't need it.
The sewing line is symmetrical.
Because we are actually in a state of front and back symmetry.
Then we create the sewing line.
Okay,
before sewing,
before starting the simulation,
put the two panels around the model's arm.
This is why I just said that our posture is best T-pose.
Because the horizontal and vertical panels,
when it uses T-pose,
you don't need to use the arrangement point to put it around the model.
Then at this time,
we will see that there are some oblique wrinkles on the shoulders.
This wrinkle,
we are going to adjust it later.
If you want to adjust it,
we can adjust it through the adjustment of the panel.
For example,
now I am in the horizontal and vertical position,
this fold is already very obvious.
Then when I change to A-pose,
this fold will be more obvious.
Right?
Then we may have to go back to T-pose.
Then adjust this fold.
In fact,
there is one of the most fundamental reasons for this fold.
Is it?
Look,
this fold is a fold that is shaped like this.
Right?
A triangle fold.
Then it is in this direction,
in this position,
there is no excess amount of this fold.
Right?
That is to say,
the deepest place of this fold is under the leaf.
So it is long under the leaf.
There are more under the leaf,
so there will be such a fold.
What we are going to do is
move this point of the shoulder line down a little bit,
remove this extra triangle part.
Then we can move this shoulder line down a little bit,
adjust it a little bit.
The back and the front are going to match.
So when you finish changing the front,
remember that the back also needs to be adjusted symmetrically.
Then the sleeve part is also to match the length of this sleeve,
which is the length of the sleeve hole here.
If you look at it again now,
this fold is gone.
This is when you are changing the board,
you may need to consider
which direction of the fabric it is in.
Which direction of the fabric is more,
you just put it in which direction.
This line is to shorten it a little bit.
But in the end,
I still keep it in this fold position.
I think this fold is not very important.
And I need to keep this fold,
so I still use this board.
Then,
let's talk about some
sleeves that are often seen
in Han clothes or ancient clothes.
First of all,
I just drew a horizontal vertical board,
so its sleeve is very large.
If I want its sleeve to be narrowed,
I will move this point at the bottom of the sleeve up.
In this way,
its sleeve will be narrowed here.
Next is the loom.
The loom is actually
when you add some points,
add some curve points,
and then give it
the curve is drawn out.
Then,
the loom is like this,
its bottom is a bit curved,
so you give it a little more fabric here,
and then a little less fabric here.
The sleeve here,
it is in my natural state,
it will not shrink here.
It is a flat sleeve like this.
If you want to make it a wide sleeve,
that is,
a little bigger sleeve,
we will make the sleeve a little longer here.
Then,
because we just talked about it,
our front and back
are in a symmetrical relationship.
So,
when you change the front,
the back will also be changed together,
and it will be adjusted automatically.
In the case of a wide sleeve,
in fact,
when you search for the Hanfu sleeve pattern,
there will be a lot of pattern patterns.
Then,
in the case of Hanfu,
it is actually very straight,
very straight.
What does the sleeve look like
when you see it with your own eyes?
What you draw
is that it is also like this.
So,
you can completely
add that picture to the background,
and then follow that picture
to hook the pattern.
OK.
Then,
there are some
little friends will say,
oh,
then my sleeve,
if I want it to have some shrinkage,
that is,
in the sleeve,
it has some wrinkles,
small wrinkles come out.
The reason for this
is because
now we have this sleeve,
you don't have any version to limit it.
It is a long sleeve,
so it won't have wrinkles here.
Then,
if we put the long sleeve
of this long section
here,
and sew a short version,
then it will have
the effect of shrinking,
that is,
there will be wrinkles along here.
In fact,
you have to think clearly,
that is,
the basic logic of wrinkles is
that in this position,
if there is more fabric,
it will form a wrinkle.
That is,
there is a long and short gap of fabric,
or in this direction,
the fabric is more than the original size,
it will be like this.
So,
we now sew a short version
of the front and back panels together,
it will have a seam line
along the sleeve position.
Oh,
not a seam line,
there will be wrinkles.
Today,
my friends,
watching this video
is also very hard,
because
in fact,
there are a lot of things
that I have to talk about
in this set of Hanfu.
That is,
this set of summer clothes.
Okay,
then,
because you can see
that our sleeves
are now flat on the top,
right?
It has a lot of bottom,
so no matter what,
your wrinkles,
that is,
the wrinkles you see
are flat.
But the wrinkles at the bottom
are curved like this,
because this line is long,
this line is short,
so it will have such a curve.
Then,
if I now want it
to be like a lantern sleeve,
I will make it
straight on the top
and straight on the bottom.
Then,
the length of these two lines
will not be too different.
It is an ordinary lantern sleeve.
We can take a look at
the shape of this sleeve
below the A-pose.
Oh,
below the A-pose,
we now have this sleeve,
this is the shape
of this sleeve,
and this is the shape
of this sleeve.
So,
we now have this sleeve,
its drooping situation
is that
it will have some droopings
along this direction,
right?
That is because
our sleeves
now have a lot of length
as well as
this
width.
Then,
when we usually
make some
clothes
that are not
or fast-fitting clothes,
they usually
pull the fabric
up,
that is,
down in the sleeve.
So,
we will have to
copy this
for this work.
Agora,
because in the next part,
we add in
the shoulder strap
or gloves,
so,
we won't
let it with
some extra cloth
here.
This is because
otherwise it will have some
holes for this work.
For this work,
we will
sew the sleeve
and the sleeve
on the sleeve
of this sleeve
for this performance.
Ok.
This is
the shape
This is what we might use for those, for example, those short ones that look like blocks.
It can't be said that it's short, it's a bit like folded sleeves, and then we can just go back and look at it.
Now, in the case of our board, it is in such a vertical position.
This line, because the fabric was worn on the body just now, its shoulder line is long.
So it's going to fall like this, it's going to flow down like this, and then along this line, it's flat here.
But because the fabric has its own gravity, it will let the sleeve fall down, right?
Then we have this line, in fact, you will feel that there is a little more fabric here, that is, there is a little more fold here.
Because here it is a very smooth line, there is a lot of fold here.
That is to say, this line is long.
If this line is long,
we will shorten it, and then we will shorten this line, and then we will shorten it, and then we will shorten this line, and then we will shorten it, and then we will shorten it.
You can let it, this is the part that is too much, the part that is too rough, adjust it,
don't let it have too much fabric to fall down like this.
Okay, and then there's the bottom of the page, because we just drew a relatively large sleeve.
Then we are doing this.
It's the whole thing.
The shape is relatively close or it doesn't have such a big sleeve.
And this version we are doing now is a relatively short version.
Then we will also shorten the sleeve here.
Then when we go to start the simulation, I may manually drag the panel to make some of these folds for it.
Then when I get to the ideal state, I will click on the panel with the W key to create some fixed needles.
Let this fold remain.
I think it's in the right place.
Then in my overall shape, I think it's OK.
I will use the shape to solidify the fold to maintain the current state.
So that when I start the simulation later on, the fold will not fall off.
I don't need to use the fixed needle anymore.
Because the fixed needle, it follows your grid.
And then if you adjust the panel, for example, after adding the internal line, this structure, the position of its fixed needle may change.
Then there will be some pull.
So I usually will solidify the pattern.
So that it can both maintain our fold and it can participate in the simulation.
OK, then let's talk about it.
Sometimes we see that this sleeve is not straight down.
It may have some special ones.
For example, it is in the position of the elbow.
It will have a circle.
Just like this in my video.
It will have a circle that expands outward first.
Then it will be collected.
This is the effect.
When you reflect on the panel.
You can first cut a internal line in the middle.
Then cut it open.
After cutting it open, spread it out a little bit along this inner line.
So that when it goes in this overall form, it will expand outward first and then collect it.
Do you understand?
OK.
Then because I talked about it before.
It's still the same thing.
If we.
This angle.
The sharp corners will be protruding out like this
So we will make two curves here
When the corners are joined together at 90 degrees
There will be no more sharp corners
For the bottom here, we can add some curve points to adjust
Otherwise, there will be a sharp corner here
If you adjust it to a 90 degree angle, it will be better
After we disassembled the sleeve into two parts
There is another advantage
We can use the bottom of the freezer
To make the top part of the plate only be created in this range
Then on this basis
We will make the upper sleeve plate a little longer
It will be better
There will be some additional folds here
Because it was naturally curved just now
Then we let it increase its length in this direction
There will be some folds here
There will be more folds here
This is some adjustment about the sleeve part
After that, we will start to wear clothes
Before we wear clothes
May give clothes first
To apply the shrinkage
Let it become a tight structure
So that it is convenient for us to
Cover other plates outside
Then make it tight
After that, we will freeze these plates
Then our shrinkage has a direction
Basically, the plate you created in MD
The horizontal direction is the end direction
The vertical direction is the end direction
Do some shrinkage for it
Then paste the inner layer of the plate
If the inner layer of the plate is pasted
It is very easy
Just look at some arrangements
Then rearrange it
After that
We may combine its front and back
Because now this plate
There are two separate plates on the left and right
Then we created
In fact, this inner layer of clothing
It is like this
It is a whole structure
We will get a straight line
Shall we cut it later?
Of course, we have to combine this plate first
Let's make it bring it together
Then we can make some cut
Cut here
You can cut from 2D to 3D
If you want to cut in 3D
Because the copied plate
Will inherit its shrinkage property
So we have to put the shrinkage first
Return to a hundred percent
Then we can make the plate slightly
Make it bigger
Make it wider
No, this outfit won't be a complete demonstration, just like in the live broadcast, because I didn't record the video of the complete demonstration from beginning to end.
But basically I have skipped the repetitive steps, so you can watch this video.
Then we use the sculpting line tool to make a direct cut of a 3D window and draw a cut line.
For the sculpting line tool, you can make a cut directly on the board when you sculpt the sculpting line.
You don't need to make a 3D drawing and then cut the board like before.
Okay, now we have half of the front of it.
Then press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical board for it.
Then we sew it on the side and fix it.
Don't let it fall apart like this.
Okay, for the sculpting line tool, because the front part is cut directly,
the back part doesn't have a cut line.
For the back part, we use the sculpting line tool to add points to the actual position of the sculpting line.
There will be a cut point here.
Then we can adjust its scale according to this cut point.
Just draw some internal lines to adjust its position.
Okay.
Then cut off the excess part.
Now we can see that we haven't made the side of the board yet.
When we add the side of the board to the horizontal direction of the collar,
its position will match our virtual model.
It's actually very easy to make the side of the board.
In order to make the side of the board more suitable for the virtual model,
we can choose these sides directly.
Then select the expansion of the board outline.
Then set a width.
This width is the width of the collar structure on the side and the width of the border structure.
After expanding the outline of the board,
remember to select the production internal line.
We can adjust this board.
Then cut along this internal line.
We can quickly create this border.
There is an advantage to creating borders like this.
If you sew it directly to a rectangular shape,
the structure of the square shape will not match the position of its shoulder line.
Now we are creating the board according to its original shape.
Then it will be more suitable for your virtual model.
Then on the side of the line,
if there is an extra part,
then we can actually use these two points to make it more suitable for your virtual model.
For example, like this point,
we can see that there is an extra part on this side.
Then we will move this point down a little bit.
Then simulate it.
Let it match.
Then the back is the same.
Adjust it.
Then simulate it again.
You can see that it will now fit the shoulder line of the virtual model.
Okay, then this sleeve,
in fact, there is not much to talk about.
This sleeve is the same as the sleeve we just talked about.
And this side of the sleeve,
there are some creases.
These creases are because the length of the sleeve is relatively long.
It is larger than the original arm length of your model.
After you adjust it,
the excess amount will be piled up here in the arm.
Then we make it a belt.
Next, we need to understand the skirt.
Or how to make a skirt with creases.
The skirt with creases is a little different from the normal pleated skirt.
Because there will be an extra rectangular structure in the middle.
Because we can imagine this pleated skirt as a rectangular one.
And the front is sewn together.
Then on both sides,
it is a basic pleated skirt.
So we need to sew the rectangular part in the middle first.
Then the structure on the side,
we will do it like a uniform skirt.
To complete it quickly.
Okay.
After we finish the belt,
because we are making a model with a relatively large pleated skirt,
we will use the freezing to save the cost of calculation.
So we will freeze the inner layer after finishing one layer.
Then we will simulate the outer layer.
But because the belt is a more tight structure,
so we need to make some interaction between it and the inner layer.
We will activate the inner layer or freeze the inner layer.
Let it simulate it together.
At the same time, I will open the image display.
Because you usually have to pay attention in the process of simulation.
Although it is now a very tight structure,
but try to respect its pressure or the image of the force.
Its prompt.
If there are some positions,
such as the position of the belt,
its color is close to red now.
That means that the fabric of its belt part is too tight.
Because in Moments Designer,
we have no damage.
No fabric damage.
If the fabric is tight,
it will still fit on the outside of your virtual model.
But it will continue to squeeze the inner sheet.
Because your inner sheet may be in a relatively loose state.
The outer sheet is too tight.
It may be unstable.
Or this belt will automatically move to the thinnest position of the virtual model's waist.
So when making this kind of belt,
especially when it is tight,
in order to prevent excessive stretching,
you can open the hardware chart in the Alt section.
To check if its strength is reasonable.
Okay.
Then let's draw the rectangular structure in the front.
After drawing this structure,
you can place this version in the 3D window.
Also, first use free sewing to sew it one-to-one.
Then choose to apply a new fabric to it.
Control D.
After creating it,
Let it align.
This is what we usually see.
This is the flat part of the front of the mask.
Because if you draw a whole rectangular sheet first,
it may be more troublesome when you create this inner line.
Because you can't just use one line to create the inner line.
You need to divide the sheet.
Then we might as well just separate the middle part.
Then the remaining part on the side,
we can use the ordinary,
the smooth side of the sheet to complete it.
Then I'll just draw this hard version here.
Because the hard version
has a certain support.
It won't be hammered on the floor.
Then I'll give it two nails.
It can better maintain its current position.
Okay.
Then we draw a rectangular sheet
to match its length with the previous sheet.
Then choose two lines
according to the inner line generated by the curve line.
The root number of this curve line
must be three times,
for example, 15.
3 times n minus 1.
Because this is just like the math problem in elementary school.
You know.
If you want it to be 15,
you have to draw 14 lines.
If you want it to be 18,
you draw 17 lines.
You can divide it into three times.
Because when we're doing the smooth side
or the smooth side,
it's all three panels in one group.
Three panels in one group.
You see.
For example, this is the position of the fold.
This is the first panel.
Then the fold is the second panel.
Then the fold is the third panel.
This is the fold of a whole group.
Then the fold of the next group is the same.
Three in one group.
So when we draw a line,
we must also follow this rule.
After that,
just use the fold function
and then just use the smooth side.
Print it.
Then before we create the curve line,
we first simulate it in the 3D window.
First of all,
after we print and print the panel,
the panel will fold better.
After folding,
it now has such a
fold structure.
Then we put it
near the panel that needs to be folded.
Then we put it near the panel that needs to be folded.
Why do we do this?
Because if we are going to calculate the fold
while calculating the line of the curve,
it will probably be in the place of the fold
under the multiple calculations.
It will have some twists.
For example,
this fold should have been neat and tidy.
Like I am now,
lined up to sew up,
but because the line of the curve is also in effect,
and then the fold is also in effect.
it will have some penetrating problems.
Then it will lead to
it will cause the fold to be in a very smooth direction, and it will come out.
Later, we will see the effect of the fold.
We can also fix the part of the fold.
Now, after we have created it, we can look at the simulation again.
We will see that when we are making this board,
we are making this board according to the width of the belt.
Because when we are creating this rectangular board,
because three pieces are one group,
so the overall width is three times the rest of the belt.
We can take a look at this.
This is a belt.
Then we have a break point here on the belt.
It is parallel to the rectangular structure.
We can match it.
Then when we are making the rest of the part of the horse mask,
because we are going to make three times the amount of a fold,
three times the amount of a fold,
so when we are drawing a rectangular shape,
the width of this rectangular shape must also be three times the value of this.
But after we finish it,
you may find that after I finish it,
I did it according to the circumference of the belt.
Its bottom is not the kind of effect that spreads outward.
Because its width is not enough.
Its width is not enough.
Then we now want it to be in the right position at the seam line.
We want its bottom to be wider.
Then we may need to extend the board.
Why do we need to extend it?
You see, when we extend the board along the middle line here,
the overall length of the waist is not changed.
But the length of the bottom here
may be the original 1.5 times.
So when we do folding and pleating effects,
when we do folding and pleating effects,
its bottom can be extended more naturally.
There will be more fabric here.
This is why we need to extend a rectangular board.
Then we change it to a curve in the middle
in order to make this line more natural and smooth.
Then continue to choose the curve to form the inner line.
Then it is the same step.
Then we will speed up here.
Fold the board.
Then fold it first.
After folding it, sew it.
Speed up, speed up.
Okay.
Don't forget to align the board to the outer line of the board.
Add a point.
So that it will be separated one by one on the top.
Then we sew it up with one stitch.
As for the skirt part,
if you don't know how to do it,
we have a tutorial on half-body skirts before.
And then in the half-body skirt,
we have listed out a lot of the types of skirts.
If you have time later,
you can take a look.
Okay, let's talk about it now.
If we make a fold,
we find that there is a fold that is turned inside out.
For example, this line should be outside.
But because we go to the sewing process
while calculating the fold and sewing,
it causes it to be inserted inside and out.
When it comes out,
we can follow the angle of the fold to the zero.
This line
to create a fixed stitch.
Just a whole fixed stitch.
Then pull out the whole fixed stitch.
Then pull out the one that should be inside.
and then push it in
and then after a while,
remove the pin
and it will automatically fold
After that, we will give the skirt some pressure
because the bottom of our skirt
when it comes to the ground
the ground is
for example, you put the skirt like this
because we are not wearing skirts like in real life
we can pull the skirt
by hand
so we have a faster way
to make the skirt spread
which is to give the skirt some pressure
when you use the pressure
the skirt will automatically
open up slowly
and then when the skirt part
is opened up
and we reach the required position
we can reduce the pressure
so that the front of the skirt
will be
a more natural and vertical position
and the bottom will also
look more natural
so you don't have to adjust it manually
Next, let's talk about the sleeves
the sleeves are like this
sometimes we have to do this
for example,
I want to fold the sleeves
there are some folds
this is the mark
sometimes
this mark
is when you change your pose
or when you fold a lot of clothes
and then you drag the fabric
to complete this fold
it will be more troublesome
so in the early stages
when we do the folding part
we will use the inner line
to fold it
let's see how to do this
first, let's draw the inner line
after drawing the inner line
we use the inner line ruler
to draw the other inner line
after drawing
we can start
to set the angle of the fold
the same way
we use the fold tool
to set the angle of the fold
the fold direction is
this line is on top of this line
so our direction is this
of course if you are familiar with the software
you can also set it manually
this line is 0 degrees
and this line is 360 degrees
then we also print the fabric
after printing the fabric
we can see if the fabric is folded
after folding
because when you print the fabric
it will be faster
to apply the fold angle
after folding
we can use the sewing needle
to fix these two points
temporarily
after using the sewing needle
to fix them temporarily
this position
will have a fold effect
that will not fall off
after that, whether we change the position
or make other adjustments
it will not affect
the fold position
for example, after we make the sleeve
in the back, now
these inner lines
are not deleted
after we make the sleeve in the back
it will have a fold effect
and because we use the sewing needle
to fix this position
the fold will not fall off
then we can manually
drag the fabric
to make the fold effect
more obvious
then we can manually
drag the fabric
more obvious
as we paste the fabric
or Marc
to see how it looks
or we can highlight
as we paste the fabric
or
jem
to see how it looks
reduct
But to make the simulation faster, we use the GPU simulation directly.
Because it is the outermost structure now, it will not have any conflicts with the inner layer or anything.
So when I usually do the costume, I will freeze the inner layer when I do the inner layer.
Then when I do the outer layer, I will directly use the GPU simulation to simulate.
Yes, if the inner line is folded, we will often use this function.
Then the structure on the other side is the same.
Okay, now after we finish folding, you see that there is a part of the sleeve here that is missing.
That's because we just folded it, and the sleeve is actually relatively shortened.
After it is shortened, we will directly use the outermost expansion.
Why do we use the outermost expansion?
After the outermost expansion, it will not affect the original structure of your board.
It will not affect the previous sewing lines or these folds.
But if you directly use the shrink function to shrink this sleeve,
For example,
If you want to widen it horizontally,
Then these lines and the position where the sewing needle is may be affected.
This is what we don't want to see.
So we usually just use the outermost expansion.
This will not affect the original part.
It's just along the original direction to widen the extra part and cut it out.
Then we will finish the calculation on this layer and finally start the simulation.
Then you will see my fabric panel board here.
I will recycle it.
Because the refurbished version is completely without any shock.
It is different from the frozen part.
The frozen part will have shock.
The refurbished part is without shock.
So the sleeves and dresses won't be affected anyway.
In order to speed up the calculation, I will refurbish it.
So let's talk about why I use CPU simulation to solve the fingerprint.
It is because of the GPU simulation.
Although it is fast to simulate.
But it is just for comparison.
If I continue to use GPU simulation on this layer and don't use CPU simulation to simulate it and freeze it,
the current version of GPU simulation will have some conflict thickness settings, which will be the same as a particle monitor.
I didn't do the final product output and didn't make the particle monitor very low,
so the thickness of the air wall around the board will be relatively high.
In this way, the texture will not be detailed enough, so we usually finish one layer.
That is, when you are making this board,
now when you are solving this board on the outermost layer, you use GPU simulation to solve it,
but when you finish this layer, you cut it into CPU simulation, solve it again, and freeze it.
The frozen board will no longer have deformations and adjustments,
so it doesn't matter if we solve it with CPU simulation.
Just freeze it.
Then we do the same thing on the outermost layer.
When you are doing the outermost layer, you can see that I will demonstrate here
why I created a board directly and then sewed it up,
instead of extending it outwards with its bottom white.
It is because when you extend it, it extends along the original grid direction.
If this board itself has some folds in this position,
and then you adjust the grid along this direction,
then you can see that this board itself has some folds in this position,
and then you can see that this board itself has some folds in this position,
so in order to avoid this problem,
and the problem that may occur with the horizontal line,
we will manually make the board and then sew it up.
This way, you can also adjust the structure of the lower part more conveniently,
and then finally we can merge it together.
And this is the same method as before.
The collar is also extended outwards and cut out.
In this case, let's talk about how to make the collar part in the end.
This is the feeling of some small folds.
First of all, the particle diameter of my collar is not very low.
The particle diameter of my entire suit is actually about 10 to 15.
It is a relatively high particle diameter,
but it still has such a small,
like in real life sewing,
there is a feeling of pulling,
because I made it a double-layer collar structure.
In this case, we should pay attention when making the collar layer.
We use the outer part of the collar for the outer layer.
We use the inner part of the inner layer for the inner layer.
In this way, the inner layer of our collar
will not make more crossings in the middle of these two layers.
Because if we don't make the outer layer of this layer,
but the inner layer,
this is the outer layer of our collar,
That's like the two of them are in normal crossings.
But if I make a layer of the inner layer,
they will already be in theika position
in the middle of the outer layer
that has more layers,
so it may not be stable.
So we make the outer layer
and make the inner layer
to be shoot out from the outer layer,
then the outer layer
then make the inner layer
to be shoot out from the outer layer,
and then simulate it.
After we create a new layer, first of all, we can use the rule 8 function.
The rule 8 function, when we set the shrink rate to positive, we can apply some smear along the negative line.
The rule 8 is like this, when the shrink rate is positive, the position of the smear will be a little magnified according to the value of the shrink rate you set.
When the shrink rate is magnified along the negative line, there will be more material here, and there will be more material here.
After we solve the problem, we will look at the simulation, and when we lower the particle scale, there will be some effect along these two sides.
There are also some small wrinkles and so on.
You can see,
it is different from the single-layer structure.
Now, if we look at it from the front, you can clearly feel that it has some thickness in the smear position.
Because the rule 8 function, it is a whole grid.
It is equivalent to the fact that the grid on both sides has been widened a little.
Then the overall structure of it may be thicker.
So when we make a collar,
if you want to make this kind of,
it is,
if you look at it from the front, it has a little bit of the thickness of the fabric,
instead of being flat,
like this plate inside,
it is a flat thin piece.
If it is outside, it will look more realistic.
Then we will definitely make it a two-layer structure.
It doesn't matter.
In fact, you will find that we still used the shrink rate afterwards.
After using the grid, we used the shrink rate.
But before using the shrink rate,
I have mentioned that in the software of Marvelous Designer,
the version you created,
the general vertical direction,
that is, you look at this arrow,
we are going to use the editing text tool to look at this arrow.
The vertical direction is our gold,
and then the horizontal direction is the tail.
Then we need to adjust the direction of this fabric.
Why?
It's because if I want this collar to have a wrinkle,
right?
Then my wrinkle must be along this line.
That is, there are not many wrinkles piled up in this direction.
If I want to have wrinkles along this line,
then I must have more fabric in this line,
in this direction.
So I will give this arrow to it,
just let it match,
as much as possible,
so that the board is only in this direction,
or this direction is affected.
So I will adjust its diagonal direction.
Then we can go through,
through the vertical wrinkle,
let this board,
on this diagonal direction,
to expand this fabric.
Because if you are,
that is, this direction is still a diagonal direction,
then when you apply the wrinkle to it,
it will expand the board diagonally,
a bit similar to that structure.
Then the wrinkle you produce
may have some lines,
that is,
twist,
and stretch,
that kind of feeling.
Then we must hope that its wrinkle is,
only in this direction,
there is a wrinkle.
So we will manually adjust this fabric direction.
I will go to this fabric direction,
just let it,
to match your board.
Okay,
then we will talk about this belt side.
Then the belt side,
is because I,
first,
put this belt,
arranged around the model.
Then I,
through our direction,
when you modify the direction,
it will have some,
like this,
twist.
This twist,
is the last thing I want,
this,
this belt,
the part of the lining,
like this,
is,
the effect of the oblique.
Then sometimes,
I actually,
just casually,
I don't have a,
that is,
already determined,
what structure I must do,
I just,
maybe,
thought of,
oh, I want to do this,
well,
like,
this piece,
this,
well,
the fabric inside,
here,
the same,
this kind of stack,
then I might use this,
well,
arrange it around the model first,
then,
use the direction,
to complete,
this,
well,
the oblique structure.
Then it is the same,
well,
it is the same as what I said before,
when we are doing the outermost layer,
if you only,
only modify this layer,
you can use GPU modeling.
Then,
use the leather,
that is,
full grain leather,
this fabric,
well,
at the beginning,
it will be less wrinkled,
because its bending strength is relatively high,
then,
we should,
lower its bending strength,
otherwise,
it will be too hard,
that is,
there is no wrinkle at all,
then,
we will set it,
after setting it,
well,
we use the fixing pin,
temporarily,
to fix its point,
then,
sew these two points together,
well,
why do we sew it together?
It is because,
in the future,
we may use these two to fix,
delete the fixing pin,
then,
look at its current structure,
if we sew it,
in this position,
is it,
itself,
it,
것을,
that,
there,
함,
YES,
Great!
OK,
if there is concern
whether or not
we need to fill a hole
in it,
then,
it will be kontrol,
return,
다,
and return
After sewing, the belt version is also the same, just like I said before, our belt may also have a double-layer structure like a collar.
Before that, we may need to use CPU simulation to calculate it twice.
When we are adjusting the size of the belt, we will use GPU simulation to calculate it, and when we need to refine it, we will use CPU simulation to calculate it.
We need to pay attention to the belt that comes out of the collar.
Because the belt that comes out of the collar will have its own sewing line.
We mentioned before that in order to make the simulation more stable, it is best not to cross-layer sewage.
In order to make the simulation more stable, it is best not to cross-layer sewage.
What does cross-layer sewing mean?
This sewing line, for example, is one layer, and there is another layer on the back, and it is still there.
Don't make the sewing line with one layer, otherwise it may be unstable to a certain extent.
We will change the sewing line manually.
Of course, this is a more detailed adjustment.
You should also pay attention when making clothes.
It is best not to cross-layer sewage.
It is best to cross-layer sewage between the two layers of the
seam allowance.
After we create it here, why do we need to make two layers?
This is the last panel here.
You can see this panel outside.
Well, the last panel I made actually has a lot of wrinkles piled up in this kind of
pattern.
It also has a waistband in the middle, which is a little bit of a constraint.
It has a lot of fabric, some shrinkage, stretch, and some wrinkles.
Why does it have wrinkles like this?
It's because we've finally increased the shrinkage of its golden line, and it will
have some wrinkles along this direction.
If you just make a single layer, it will not be able to make this structure, so you
must have a bottom layer panel to limit the wrinkles.
If you want to make a single layer, you must have a bottom layer panel to limit the wrinkles.
the bottom layer will limit the seam allowance of the top layer
and then the outer layer will use the shrink to
stack the fabric in this range
so that we will have this kind of fold effect
this is also why I want to do double layers here
then we do the outer layer
every time I do the outer layer, I just copy the inner layer to the outer layer
and then because you copied this layer
in fact, now you have more panels
then this kind of panel structure
if you directly copy and paste it
it may have some impact
then we will let it be in a flat form
arrange the panels and then simulate
just like usual
it is not the same with the arrangement point
because it is a whole large piece of panel
then simulate
then we have to pay attention when we simulate
in the process of simulation
you either let it simulate once
or you don't go to the second press
and then simulate
why?
because you are like me just now
to show you
if you just simulate once
it is like this
but if you stop the simulation
and then simulate it again
the second time when you calculate
it will admit that your sewing line is sewn together
it will pass by all of a sudden
it will be unstable
then we instead of
like if it happened just now
then you just ctrl z back to before
then we manually place the panels here
how to place this
like the shoulder here
we just had some stretch
right?
our sewing line is like this
you can look at the length of this sewing line
it is this section
one by one sewing line
then the shoulder side
its panel is relatively small
and we finally hope that this shoulder
it is the position of the force
it will be at the bottom
there will be some panels
it is sagging right?
then our shoulder here
let it try to touch
to be able to quickly let the shoulder here
stabilize
and then hang on the virtual model
because these two panels
for example, like the side here
it is farther away
its sewing line
is two points
slowly
the closer it is
the longer the time
then in such a case
we will sew the shoulder here first
then the bottom here
then slowly simulate it
then we will wait for it to simulate
then before the simulation
we can put it first
set some shrink values
for it to change back
then let it simulate in one time
do not simulate in the process
in the simulation process
pause
then simulate in two times
just let it slowly
slowly simulate itself
stabilize
that's it
after it simulates
we will start to make the collar
then the collar here
I am considering
that is we are doing a modern style of clothing
in fact, there are all kinds of collar structure
many times for example
there is a standing collar
there is also that kind of folding
a little bit like a modern collar
that kind of collar structure
that in this kind of collar structure
you have to pay attention to
consider the position of your fold
for example, now this collar
we are a fold over structure
right
that it as a fold over structure
with its sewn panel
this point
it will not be particularly
outside
it is basically
this position
is near its fold position
so we will push its shoulder point
a little bit inside
so that it does not go too far away from the model
but if you want to make the collar
is a certain distance from the model's neck
then we are adjusting this shoulder line
when you pay attention to this point
you may have to move a little bit outside
then we will start to make the collar
so before we make the collar
we can first make a point
this point
is the fold position of our collar
then you can see
the overall movement
is it the movement you want
if we draw a triangle-shaped panel
or draw a rectangular panel
to sew this collar
is not very convenient
so we usually
draw the shape of the collar
that I want
on the large panel
and then hook it up
for example
if I want to make a collar
like this
I will draw it on the panel
oh
this collar is about this size
then hook it up with the hook and loop tool
then you can refer to
the position of the collar at the end
okay
after that
we will use the hook and loop tool
to make the collar part of the line
to be selected
then right-click to select the hook and loop panel
then put the panel together with the panel
at this time
you have to pay attention
that our collar part
is actually a flipped structure
so in the end
we will turn the surface of this panel
so that it can keep
the direction of its hair line is the same
because the panel we hook up now
it is
uh
it is facing out
but in fact
our collar is usually facing back
so we have to turn the hair line
uh
just turn it over
to keep its hair line direction is the same
this is how a collar is done
okay
then we have other collar structures
for example
I need to make a collar now
this collar
in fact, the collar I just made
and the one I want at the end
stand up
a little big
this kind of flipped collar
is a different structure
uh
it is a different structure
then we can start to
try this collar
how to do
that everyone
it is
we
may
uh
is not a lot of
this clothing
version of
knowledge
that we do
how to do it
first of all
we can try
to use the collar just now
that
similar
panel
just sew it a little longer
sew to the back collar
and then take a look
this is what I'm doing
to simulate
if we don't have the pattern knowledge
I now need it again
is a collar structure like this
I'll make a triangle first
and then sew it to the collar here
that's what we did
at the beginning of this tutorial
the same
when we are making the collar
don't sew it together
with the one in the back
first
just let it be one-to-one
after sewing
let's take a look
at this panel
in the natural
state
can it be one
or the other
is a more
appropriate
ideal state
and then put it together
in the back
here
I sewed the triangle panel
after sewing
let's observe
in fact
no matter how I adjust
this collar
is it
all a short
it can't stand up
this collar
it will definitely
fall down
because
there is no support
in the back
this structure
is there
that is
I have to have
such a corner
just this side
finally
why can it
stand up
because
this side
is in the back
so
we adjust the structure
for it
and then
simulate it
ok
now
we have
a certain
thickness
in the back
here
is
we just
put it
here
made a corner
right
this panel
was a triangle before
so
it will fall down
in the back
now
we made a corner
for it here
so it can stand up
ok
we can now
give it a fixed needle
first maintain
the current shape of this collar
and then
harden the collar
so
in fact
we don't need
to have a very
good understanding
of this pattern
you can try
it out
a little bit
for example
you draw a triangle
draw a square
and then
finish it
draw it first
Let's go ahead and install it, and you can see where there is a little bit of a change, and then give it a little bit of a change.
Okay, now that I've installed it, this point was supposed to be in the back.
Now we have this extra part, which is equivalent to a part of the back neck here.
That's the same. We're just a little bit.
According to the effect of the 3D window, the hard version is actually a simulation.
Because the hard version is equivalent to a higher bending strength.
It's equivalent to adding a material attribute with a bending strength of about 80.
It will naturally stand up like this.
So if we want to do the final structure effect of the collar here, we're going to hard this collar.
Then flip the other side over and simulate it.
Finally, after we've simulated it,
we're going to sew it together in the back.
Of course, if you don't sew it in the back, you can turn it to the back and take a look at it.
That's because I have a certain amount of experience in making panels.
I might feel it here in the back.
Just stand it up like this.
I'll take a look.
Okay, so now we have a shoulder point here, right?
Then we go back to the panel and you can see that it's a sharp corner here, so it will protrude out.
The part that protrudes out like this.
If I don't want it, I'm going to make a flat 90-degree corner here.
And then there's the collar part.
I made a curve here.
It's the same as when we started making this collar, which is the innermost collar.
If this line is a straight line, its corners don't turn round like this.
It's all sharp, sharp, sharp.
Then we must hope that it's 90 degrees here.
It's not going to protrude out like this.
So we still have to make it a curve.
Then this collar is step by step.
We finally finished the effect of sharpening the collar.
And then if what we want to do is some fresh wind clothing, its collar is completely straight.
Then we can use the fixed needle tool to drag the collar down like this.
It will eventually have a sharpening effect.
This is actually the end of this video.
Basically, the collar that is common in fresh wind clothing is about this.
Including the inner layer of the collar that we talked about before.
I also tried to show you how to make these collars.
Let's see where we are.
Wow, we've already talked about half of it.
Okay.
After that, let me think about what's next.
After I sit here, I may be thinking about adding something to it.
And then it's still the same.
Don't forget the collar we made.
When you open the single-sided display, you will see that the collar is facing the outside.
Don't forget to align its hair line.
Okay.
Yes, I only talked about half of it.
There are many other things left.
The collar is simple in its shape.
But it has a lot of details to talk about.
And then there is the collar.
When you turn the collar, we can see that it is naturally curved.
The point we just used to turn the collar.
it will always fall out, it will fall out, right?
In this case, we are going to
re-create a line that is used to fold,
and then set a folding angle for it
to make its fold
be able to fold accurately from the point we set.
So we need to draw a line
and then set it along the fold position of this collar,
otherwise it will fold directly according to your sewing line.
It must be folded,
that is, the direction of its fold must not be enough
to match the shape of our neck.
So we will manually draw a line inside,
and then we can adjust this line inside a little bit.
This is where we can refer to the position
where it should have been folded in the 3D window.
Refer to this position,
how do we refer to it?
You can take a look at the point on the left.
Did I drag it over just now?
We will
go back to the steps I did before.
This is now here.
It is naturally
in the case of naturally folding,
there will be an extra part of the fold here.
Let's drag this place and drag it here a little bit.
After dragging it a little bit,
this natural fold line
should have been a fold line.
Is it displayed?
Then I pointed at this blue dot.
In fact, this is a
I set it,
such as the position of the anchor point or reference point.
When I draw the inner line,
I will intentionally draw the inner dot
to approach the position of this blue dot.
So that the fold line I finally identified
will be more suitable for the fold position I want.
After that, we just draw this inner line,
and then adjust its curve point,
and then set the folding angle for it.
Then, because our final version
is to keep the direction of the line consistent,
so now I need to turn it over on the surface.
Otherwise, if I turn it over on the surface later,
we will have to reconsider its folding line.
Now I will put this inner line
because we are here now
is equivalent to folding the back to the outside,
so we need to set a fold angle
greater than 180 degrees.
After setting it, you can see that
after I re-draw this inner line
and after setting it,
the fold is now more suitable for the shape we want,
and the fold is more straight in this position, right?
So when we usually make this collar,
we may need to pay a little attention to it.
We can intentionally use the inner line
and the fold angle to make its shape more ideal.
Then there is a new feature,
which is in the 2024 version,
this is the posture we brought ourselves on the Kinect mall.
In fact, I didn't adjust the posture manually.
I just used a common posture,
and then the shape of the hand,
I used the shape of the grip,
and then in the 2024 version,
we can choose to only insert the hand when we insert the posture separately.
Then you can download a grip posture from the mall.
In this way, you don't have to manually adjust the grip, right?
You can just use it directly.
Okay, now after we have simulated it,
don't forget to simulate it in the CPU,
because each layer of us is finally finished with the CPU simulation,
and then the new layer is simulated with the GPU.
Then we finally activate all the panels,
and then import the posture in,
and then use the CPU simulation to calculate.
Okay, after this calculation,
the size of the overall clothing is already there.
And if you want some dynamic effects,
you may be in it,
not completely simulated,
hammer down,
just these sleeves,
it still has some dynamic effects,
you can pause the simulation.
But for me,
it's waiting for it to be all simulated,
and then go to do this,
the bottom layout of our clothes,
some of these effects.
And then before that,
because we're going to do those dynamic effects at the end,
so I'm going to start from the very bottom layer,
layer by layer.
Not from the bottom layer,
but gradually from the outer layer,
to return its shrink rate to 100.
Because our previous shrink rate,
it's all,
we let the clothes shrink,
to make it easier for the outer layer to fit on it.
So now we're going to layer by layer,
return its shrink rate to the original shrink rate.
So we can try to make it,
some of the original wrinkles,
to occur.
And then when we return the shrink rate to 100,
you have to pay attention,
don't forget to let the two layers of the board,
is to activate the simulation together,
so that they interact with each other.
This way,
the fabric will be more natural.
And then if there are some parts of the fabric that are sticky,
you can manually fix it.
Okay,
after that,
it's,
in the inner layer of the board,
we also layer by layer,
to untangle it,
and then simulate it like this.
And then we put the shrink rate,
because when we reduce the shrink rate,
it doesn't matter,
because it's just,
we can reduce the shrink rate from 100 to 80.
But if you want to return the shrink rate to 100,
because our costume structure,
it has a lot of fabric,
and there are a lot of layers of fabric,
and there are a lot of fabric overall grid numbers.
In this case,
when we return the shrink rate,
we must return it step by step,
don't return the shrink rate from 80 to 100 at once,
so that your fabric will suddenly have too much,
this space comes out,
that is, the amount of fabric comes out,
in this case,
it may be unstable,
so when we return the shrink rate from 80 to 100,
we return it step by step,
not return it to 100 at once.
Of course,
you can also try it,
that is,
you can return it to 100 at once,
take a look,
and then if it touches it,
it's unstable,
then you can just return it,
change it from 80 to 85,
and then change it to 100 little by little.
In the case of the outer layer,
we may apply a new fabric to it,
because we may not let this plate freeze for a long time afterwards,
and it may give it a higher bending strength.
Also, when you usually do,
that is, when you say you are doing costume,
it will look like this,
for example, the overall shape of my clothes,
like the deep blue sleeve part on the innermost layer,
it has a sense of verticality, right?
It's like this, a lot of layers, right?
But when we apply this layer of sand on the outer layer,
and the outer layer of this shoulder structure,
it has a clear sense of support here.
Like this sense of support and this hard structure,
it's because we used a fabric with a higher bending strength,
it will have such a sense of support.
So when we apply these plates to physical properties,
we will intentionally apply different physical properties to them.
For example, for the inner layer,
we may apply a default fabric to it,
or manually reduce its bending strength,
manually reduce its bending strength,
and the strength of the fine sand.
And then this layer, we use Eugen Sand.
Eugen Sand itself has a relatively high bending strength.
It will have some support.
And then on this side,
we may use a material with a higher bending strength,
that is, physical properties,
so that it has a support.
So we may use different materials for each layer.
For example, I will manually increase its bending strength a little bit.
Then we simulate it and take a look.
It will slowly support up.
And because we sewed it up here,
so it will also have some support along the position of the wrinkle line.
And then during the simulation process,
we can drag the plate
so that it will slowly support up.
And then during the simulation process,
I suddenly found that this clothes,
because its plate is heavier,
so it may have some bending strength.
When there is bending strength,
we can adjust it little by little to repair it.
Then we just move it down a little bit.
And then we can fix it.
OK, and this is like this,
it's the same here.
It has this obvious point of the shoulder,
when we poke it out,
we just move this point down a little bit.
Let it fit more with the arm curve we need.
It's the same.
This is what we do in the final solution.
Then we have a complete solution.
In the beginning, you can use the GPU simulation to simulate,
and in the middle and late stages, you may need to switch to CPU simulation to simulate.
But don't worry, our GPU simulation is in the process of optimization.
As I mentioned earlier, we will use the Ogen-SHA material to simulate again.
Its bending strength is relatively high.
Ogen-SHA is similar to the default Ogen-SHA,
but the default Ogen-SHA has a certain difference.
In addition, after we change the material properties,
we will need to activate the related materials,
and do some collision with the frozen part.
So here I will activate the seal and belt of the waist.
At this time, I found that there were some unstable and shaking problems.
Let's take a look at how to fix this.
First of all,
it is possible to self-calculate a small part of the cross-section.
And then,
we may need to harden the plate
of the collar part of the cross-section.
And then, because the plate is hardened,
its bending strength is relatively high.
In the case of a relatively high bending strength,
its fold will be relatively small.
Its fold is relatively small,
so it is not easy to have instability.
After that,
we can use the selection grid tool
to select some grid surfaces and drag them out.
For example, there are some cross-sectional grid surfaces here.
We will try to organize them as much as possible.
When selecting the grid,
try to select it in the 2D window.
Because when selecting the grid in the 3D window,
it is impossible to select the back side.
So we go to the 2D window to select this grid,
and drag it out in the 3D window.
Then wait for it to simulate.
After that,
the collision and instability part itself
can be adjusted by hardening,
and it will slowly simulate stability.
So to summarize,
the key point is that
when you find that the two layers of the plate have a cross-section,
when we have a cross-section before we return it,
first we harden these two layers of the plate
to reduce its fold as much as possible.
Second,
we will use the selection grid tool
to select the cross-section of the two layers of the plate.
And then,
we will use the selection grid tool
to select the cross-section of the two layers of the plate.
The first layer is the third layer,
so the last layer is the third layer.
The third layer is the fourth layer.
Then we can choose a new layer,
and we can drag it out in the third layer.
Then let it be far away from the inner layer on the outer layer,
and drag it out to the outer layer as much as you can,
and then wait for it to simulate.
After that,
there may be some physical adjustment.
For example,
I need it to have a stronger
it will be more likely to fall down.
On the other hand, if you want it to look harder
or more delicate,
you will need to increase the strength of the fascia and the strength of the corneal line.
The weight, or density,
depends on the size of the fascia.
If the fascia is too heavy,
the texture will be more obvious.
If the density is lower,
the fabric itself will look lighter
and more loose.
In the process of simulation,
I found that the weight of the fabric itself is higher
than the weight of the fascia.
So my handmade fabric
is 27 or 30cm,
which is the most suitable size for this shape.
So my handmade fabric is 27 or 30cm,
So when you want to adjust the position of the fascia,
you can use a pin
to stretch it in.
Since there are friction between the fabric and the cloth,
you need to find the most reasonable position
and drag it in.
And because there is friction between the fabrics, it will slowly bring the outer layer of the fabric to the position where it should be worn.
After it is worn, we will freeze it and then manually adjust the outer layer of the fabric.
Of course, in fact, before you start changing the movement, you can consider that it may happen because the clothes are heavier.
If you want to drag it to one side, you can use a sewing needle to fix the position between the fabrics first.
So that it won't have any misalignment.
When I was adjusting the movement, I just forgot.
I forgot.
I didn't feel that it would affect so much.
But it doesn't matter.
Anyway, we can use this fixing needle to drag it back a little bit.
After that, we are going to start doing some...
Because now in our static state, the fabric will naturally drop and stick to our body curve.
In order to make it look more dynamic, we will make some adjustments to the outer layer of the fabric.
So that it won't fall down like I did in my video.
Here, we usually have several ways to adjust it.
There is one more.
Because now it is on the outer layer.
So we can use GPU simulation to calculate the outer layer.
The outer layer of the fabric.
And its particle diameter is 10.
It will be a little bit better.
If you use GPU simulation, its conflict density will not be too high.
And here I adjust the gravity to 0.
Because the gravity...
When we adjust the gravity to 0 in our simulation model,
we manually drag this fabric.
Its...
It won't fall down so easily due to the gravity.
So we can quickly do some counter-gravity effects.
In the previous video, there were some people who said,
Oh, how to do this counter-gravity effect?
Then we may adjust this in the case of movement.
Set its gravity to 0 first.
It will be more convenient to adjust or do some dynamic effects.
And then we mentioned it before.
We may use some functions of this shape simulation.
That is, when we make sleeves,
we will use the shape simulation function.
Then here we can also use the shape simulation function.
And now because of the shape simulation,
it has some shape simulation.
So we can use the grid function
to brush the area of the shape simulation.
Then after brushing,
we can give it a partial shape simulation.
Then in the new version,
we can also choose whether to display color.
What about the shape simulation part?
Because it is gray, we can hide it.
Okay, the posture file can be shared.
The posture file can be shared with you
when I upload this live broadcast afterwards.
The text file can also be shared.
I can integrate these fabrics and send them out.
Then you can see that
we have solidified a part of the shape.
So even if we start the simulation,
the folds that we have manually adjusted
will not be affected.
Even if I return the gravity to negative 9800,
this very deep fold,
because I used a partial shape simulation,
so it is still maintained.
So the shape simulation function
we use in the usual process,
if you have adjusted a fold that you think is ideal,
and then,
plus the fixing pin,
if you think it is too flat,
we can use the partial shape simulation
or the overall shape simulation function
to maintain the shape of the fabric
that we have adjusted.
Then, for example,
if there are some adhesions in the fabric,
we can manually repair it.
Just adjust this board.
Because you will definitely face too much fabric
when making a costume,
and then there may be some cardin problems.
So we try to go to the frozen tree
that will not participate in the simulation part
or the part that the inner layer
will not touch at all.
We can use the anti-activation function.
Then,
we can use the anti-activation function
to fix the part that will not touch at all.
We can use the anti-activation function.
Then,
including the shape simulation,
because the part of our shape simulation
will maintain the current shape very well.
Then we can,
at the end,
for example,
before you export,
before the final product is exported,
you can delete the shape simulation,
that is,
cancel it
or delete it directly.
Then,
in a short simulation,
to make it more natural.
Yes.
So,
don't forget that
you can try more in the process
of using it
to make the shape simulation
of the part
and the overall shape simulation function.
Then,
on my side,
I may,
basically,
adjust to a shape that I think is OK.
After that,
I may directly
make the shape simulation of the whole shape.
Because
after the overall shape is simulated,
I can still
give it some pressure
to make it
slightly
have some effect.
This is
some of the techniques
we often use
when we are doing
anti-gravity structure.
For example,
shape simulation,
and
shape simulation first,
then add pressure.
Because if you
add pressure directly,
the pressure is a
whole plate.
Each position
will be
more
obviously
affected.
It will be
as if it was
inflated.
But if you
use shape simulation first,
and
then
use pressure
to blow up
the plate,
its
amplitude
will be
much smaller.
Then,
for example,
there are some
interference
situations,
you can
activate the
inner plate
plate
and simulate it together
to solve
this interference problem.
Then,
it is also the same
that the particle diameter
can be
gradually
reduced.
For example,
we first
reduce the particle diameter
of the sleeve part
and then
we can continue to
freeze the plate
after the simulation
is stable.
Then,
take a look at
whether there is any
kind of
instability
or interference
around it.
There are too many layers,
and
the animation
generally
does not
wear out.
The reason why
I wear out here
is because
I have used
GPU simulation.
GPU simulation
itself
is in the
current version,
the later version
will optimize
this problem.
In the previous version,
GPU simulation
will have some
material interference
position,
because
it is different
from the calculation
result of CPU simulation,
so it may
suddenly
bounce.
But
when you
do
Hanfu,
especially
when you
do
this animation,
you must
pay attention to
the animation
movement
should not
be too big.
The animation
movement
should not
be too big.
The shape
simulation
part will be
better,
because
it maintains
this folding
shape.
It needs to
utilize
the shape
simulation
function,
and remember
to increase
the friction
a little bit.
For animation,
it depends
on the
movement
of the
five
keys.
If the movement
is not
particularly
strange,
then
remember to
pause often.
Especially
when the
key
is about
to touch
the
material,
you can
use
some
key
needles
to deal
with it.
For example,
because
the movement
is not
very
smooth,
you can
pause
and adjust
it.
Here,
I will
demonstrate
that,
for example,
we are using
the pressure
for it now,
but we are
using the pressure
of the
shape
simulation first.
You will
see that
it will not
be like
before.
If we
use
pressure,
it will
be like
this.
In addition
to
using
pressure,
we can also
use
wind blowing.
Wind blowing
is the same.
In the
new version,
our wind
has something
called
an
infinite
border
that can be adjusted.
Because
the previous version
of the wind
is automatically
opened
an infinite
border.
The infinite
border is
closed.
Now,
if you
turn off
the
infinite
border,
there will
be a
line
frame
in the
wind
control
machine.
After
the
line
frame
is
out,
you can
adjust
the
wind
blowing
range
to
set the
wind
blowing
distance
to the
wind
control
level.
So,
wind
blowing
is
the
wind
control
level of
wind
control.
And
wind
blowing
is
the
wind
control
level
of
wind
control.
For example, the upper part of the image will continue to be stylized, and the lower part of the image will not be stylized, so that it will be more natural.
For example, the upper part of the image is stylized.
The bottom is over-stylized, as I want to reduce this, so I will cancel the stylization.
Remember that the strength of the
material is very low, so please do not use stylization when the material is in various delicious numbers.
If the material has a physical property that is very easy to deform, but you don't deform it now, then the fabric will shake and it will not be stable.
But at this time, it is usually relatively rare, but you must remember that there is a condition in the guidebook.
If you have the strength of the bottom of the neck and the strength of the toes, do not use the shape optimization when the number is different.
Even if you want to use the shape optimization, you just increase the strength of the bottom of the neck and the toes a little bit.
But just increase the quality a little bit, don't use the shape optimization when the numbers are all zero.
When the animation is calculated, it is reported to the police that the storage is full, how to clean it?
You can only pause the recording, save the file, and delete the animation that was recorded before the next recording,
and then continue to record from this point on.
It is divided into sections.
You don't want to record too much at once.
There is no way to use other ways to solve this when the storage is full.
After the overall shape is calculated, continue to blow the wind or use pressure to make it slightly open.
Then the sectional shape optimization or the overall shape optimization has a setting.
The higher the intensity of the shape optimization, the more it can maintain the current shape.
The lower the intensity, the more easily it will mutate.
But it can also continue to maintain the current shape to a certain extent.
It depends on its external influence.
So shape optimization, you can look at your own needs.
For example, you want it to maintain this shape as much as possible.
But if it has to participate in the simulation at the same time,
then you have to adjust the shape optimization value to 100.
Then basically this is all the content of making this set of clothes.
Other parts, oh, it seems that it hasn't ended yet.
Wait a minute.
Let me think about it.
There should be some more parts.
I almost thought I had finished talking.
I think I was the last one.
I also made some adjustments to the edges.
Yes, that's the QQJ.
You can add it.
Oh, there's still a little bit left.
In the end, we drew an internal line.
Then why?
It's because I'm in this natural simulation state now.
Let's see.
It still has some dynamic parts here.
Then I might hope that the last part of this sleeve can be more.
It doesn't matter if it's the angle of the fold or the overall shape.
I would like it to be a little harder.
That's the position of the edge.
Then I might apply a new fabric to it alone.
Then for this fabric, I will adjust its bending strength a little higher.
Then try to bend it slightly to the wild.
OK,
at the end we will process the plate structure of the sleeve.
When we are modeling the outer layer, for example, the belt has a relatively low particle diameter, and the skirt has a relatively large internal line.
If it can't touch the sleeve, it will reactivate.
There are a lot of calculations to save on the reactivation.
So you can reactivate if you can't touch it, but if you can touch it, you have to freeze it.
Then I will also manually adjust the shape of these folds.
Of course, you can also look at the GPU model.
I'm here because this dress is almost finished, and then I'll adjust it again.
Oh, is it? If you haven't found the queue, you can send a private message to the backstage.
Because sometimes our queue number will be changed.
There is a new queue.
And then when there is something, the old group, you may not be able to find it.
So you can send a private message to the backstage.
Because I can't remember our queue number.
And then if you think this fabric is too floating, you can increase its density a little bit.
So that it will be more vertical.
And then about the material physics attribute, there are more content.
You can see it.
Let's take a look at our last live broadcast.
It's more previous.
We don't have a WeChat group.
There is no WeChat group yet.
There used to be a WeChat group, but there was no one talking in it.
And then it's inconvenient to do that file sharing and communication.
It's just that there are more queues now.
The last thing is to reduce the particle diameter and then simulate it.
There should be no other content.
We delete the internal lines in the fold position.
Then it can maintain the fold effect very well.
And then the last thing should be the belt part.
I just talked about the internal belt.
We set its shrink to do these folds.
And then you can see that it has a lot of folds.
And then because we now want its folds to be in this direction,
that is, the level of the fold is generated.
It doesn't need some Z-shaped or messy folds in this direction.
So when we adjust its shrink,
it will give it.
Oh, it's because this fabric is vertical.
So it's changed to its vertical shrink.
It will have more fabric in the vertical direction.
There will be more fabric in this direction.
Then it will have some folds.
And then why do I set the end speed to 98?
It's because you imagine it.
It's like the fabric is tightened now.
If it's tightened, it will make the fabric in this direction look more obvious.
Yeah, it's just that there's more QQ.
It must be because it's more convenient to pass documents.
You must also see it when you use the group.
I will say in the group.
Then you send me the project file.
This is a little more convenient.
If it's a working day, I will also be there.
If you have any questions, you can come to our group to ask questions.
Okay, thank you for your constant accompaniment.
Thank you for your support of Marvelous Designer.
See you in the next video.
See you in the next live broadcast.
See you next time.
Bye bye.